233-0001|We have now just talked about human AI interaction and,|We have now just talked about human AI interaction and,
233-0002|synergistically using the power of ay eye and machine learning and the power of humans to build systems that are collaborative.|synergistically using the power of ay eye and machine learning and the power of humans to build systems that are collaborative.
233-0003|But what this means is that we are going to move ay eye and deep learning research out of the benign environment of academic exercise.|But what this means is that we are going to move ay eye and deep learning research out of the benign environment of academic exercise.
233-0004|Making a transition into impacting people's lives with this type of Technology.|Making a transition into impacting people's lives with this type of Technology.
233-0005|How good is my algorithm going to compete against other methods on that specific tasks for example image classification?|How good is my algorithm going to compete against other methods on that specific tasks for example image classification?
233-0006|But now we are thinking about something that is a little bit different.|But now we are thinking about something that is a little bit different.
233-0007|Cause we are thinking about the question of how can I impact users.|Cause we are thinking about the question of how can I impact users
233-0008|How can I have an impact of benefit to society?|How can I have an impact of benefit to society?
233-0009|and to humankind in general|and to humankind in general
233-0010|when we think about this| when we think about this
233-0011|at least when some people think about this|at least when some people think about this
233-0012|Should we be afraid of something?|Should we be afraid of something?
233-0013|Yes, what should we be afraid of?|Yes, what should we be afraid of?
233-0014|Old sorcerer has vanished and for once has gone to waste|Old sorcerer has vanished and for once has gone to waste
233-0015|Spirits called by him now banished|Spirits called by him now banished
233-0016|Do you recognize this? This is from the sorcerer’s apprentice.|Do you recognize this? This is from the sorcerer’s apprentice.
233-0017|Not going to be more specific on how I think this relates to what we will be talking about| Not going to be more specific on how I think this relates to what we will be talking about
233-0018|But I hope that you will be able to make some connections.|But I hope that you will be able to make some connections.
233-0019|Here are a quick overview of the overarching problems that we need to be thinking about.|Here are a quick overview of the overarching problems that we need to be thinking about.
233-0020|We are going to use and develop ay eye and deep learning systems that affect people's lives.|We are going to use and develop ay eye and deep learning systems that affect people's lives.
233-0021|The first challenge that we need to think about are problem formulation.|The first challenge that we need to think about are problem formulation.
233-0022|We need to understand that algorithms particularly in an industry and commercialization setting are designed and deployed with certain goals in mind.|We need to understand that algorithms particularly in an industry and commercialization setting are designed and deployed with certain goals in mind.
233-0023|Companies may need to hit their production milestones. They need to have certain revenue goals. They have all sorts of different things.|Companies may need to hit their production milestones. They need to have certain revenue goals. They have all sorts of different things.
233-0024|And when they develop an algorithm when they then they when they decide to deploy deployed algorithm, they really deployed in order to achieve or make progress towards some of these goals.|And when they develop an algorithm when they then they when they decide to deploy deployed algorithm, they really deployed in order to achieve or make progress towards some of these goals.
233-0025|So the allegedly innocent accuracy that we usually report specificity or sensitivity or what have you can actually refer|So the allegedly innocent accuracy that we usually report specificity or sensitivity or what have you can actually refer
233-0026|To give you an example of what I mean when I say that is one example, consider a bank|To give you an example of what I mean when I say that is one example, consider a bank
233-0027|We would like to automate the process of assessing an applicant’s credit worthiness for a credit.|We would like to automate the process of assessing an applicant’s credit worthiness for a credit.
233-0028|Now the problem with credit worthiness is that it is a bit of a nebulous concept. It's a little unclear on what should go and what shouldn't go into a credit worthiness score.| Now the problem with credit worthiness is that it is a bit of a nebulous concept. It's a little unclear on what should go and what shouldn't go into a credit worthiness score.
233-0029|So in order to solve this problem one way of addressing this would be to redefine the problem that is actually|So in order to solve this problem one way of addressing this would be to redefine the problem that is actually
233-0030|Actually soft as a surrogate or as a proxy to come up with credit worthiness|Actually soft as a surrogate or as a proxy to come up with credit worthiness
233-0031|One way of doing this for example, would be to say. Eell. I want to define a metric the classifieds applicants for loans.|One way of doing this for example, would be to say. Eell. I want to define a metric the classifieds applicants for loans.
233-0032|Such that given a certain time span, I can maximize my profit margin.|Such that given a certain time span, I can maximize my profit margin.
233-0033|Or I can maximize the number of loans that are being repaid|Or I can maximize the number of loans that are being repaid
233-0034|Hmm and I don't have to foreclose for example house|Hmm and I don't have to foreclose for example house
233-0035|Right? This is something that can be optimized.|Right? This is something that can be optimized.
233-0036|But the problem is that if this optimization problems then it's solved completely in an unconstrained way.|But the problem is that if this optimization problems then it's solved completely in an unconstrained way.
233-0037|Then the algorithm may discover certain behavior. That for example is discriminatory or predatory.|Then the algorithm may discover certain behavior. That certain example is discriminatory or predatory.
233-0038|And you can see how this is potentially problematic and requires very well-thought-out practices to avoid this type of behavior.|And you can see how this is potentially problematic and requires very well-thought-out practices to avoid this type of behavior.
233-0039|Who is going to enforce that the auditing of these algorithms? That's a good question and maybe there is a bit of an answer at the end of the session.|Who is going to enforce that the auditing of these algorithms? That's a good question and maybe there is a bit of an answer at the end of the session.
233-0040|How we collect data and what data we collect|How we collect data and what data we collect
233-0041|that the data that we collect maybe unrepresentative of reality or the data is required by historic processes that for example are already biased.|that the data that we collect maybe unrepresentative of reality or the data is required by historic processes that for example are already biased.
233-0042|Now, for unrepresentative data, this means that we are curating a training set of our algorithm and that training set that we use to develop is unrepresentative of the target population.|Now, for unrepresentative data, this means that we are curating a training set of our algorithm and that training set that we use to develop is unrepresentative of the target population.
233-0043|For most of you this shouldn't be new we have already talked about some of these examples of the deep learning for healthcare class.|For most of you this shouldn't be new we have already talked about some of these examples of the deep learning for healthcare class.
233-0044|Gives you a dataset that potentially is unrepresentative of the target population that the algorithm would later be run on.
233-0045|A very interesting algorithm that does something that is exciting.|A very interesting algorithm that does something that is exciting.
233-0046|that, if downsample looks very similar to the images to the image that is being provided and the pixelated version|that, if downsample looks very similar to the images to the image that is being provided and the pixelated version
233-0047|It particularly gained a lot of attention because when the algorithm was fed, the pixelated image that you can see here on the bottom right|It particularly gained a lot of attention because when the algorithm was fed, the pixelated image that you can see here on the bottom right
233-0048|When presented with this image the algorithm would reconstruct the high high resolution version of this image that looks like this|When presented with this image the algorithm would reconstruct the high high resolution version of this image that looks like this
233-0049|And you could probably argue that this does not look anything like Barack Obama|And you could probably argue that this does not look anything like Barack Obama
233-0050|Another example that has gained quite a bit of attention is the Google photos feature that creates automatically albums for you|Another example that has gained quite a bit of attention is the Google photos feature that creates automatically albums for you
233-0051|Because it is highly racist. It is highly discriminatory and it affects people negatively in their everyday life.|Because it is highly racist. It is highly discriminatory and it affects people negatively in their everyday life.
233-0052|So we need to think strongly about how are we going to solve these problems going forward.|So we need to think strongly about how are we going to solve these problems going forward.
233-0053|Then we probably need to create dataset that are fair.|Then we probably need to create dataset that are fair.
233-0054|But the thing to realize is that also fair datasets can potentially result in algorithms that are anything but fair.|But the thing to realize is that also fair datasets can potentially result in algorithms that are anything but fair.
233-0055|Imagine a data set that is shows the faces because we have talked about faces in these two examples.|Imagine a data set that is shows the faces because we have talked about faces in these two examples.
233-0056|Included in this dataset, they accurately capture the demographics of, say, German| Included in this dataset, they accurately capture the demographics of, say, German
233-0057|Okay, you can see the population the demographics of Germany in 2017 in the right hand side here.|Okay, you can see the population the demographics of Germany in 2017 in the right hand side here.
233-0058|Its certainly representative right? Because it is created exactly based on the population of the demographics that we find in Germany.|Its certainly representative right? Because it is created exactly based on the population of the demographics that we find in Germany.
233-0059|but as you can see on the right hand side, the demographics in Germany is predominantly Germans, which are Caucasians, which means there are lights and white skin|but as you can see on the right hand side, the demographics in Germany is predominantly Germans, which are Caucasians, which means there are lights and white skin
233-0060|So people of color and potentially other nationalities are heavily underrepresented in that specific dateset.|So people of color and potentially other nationalities are heavily underrepresented in that specific dateset.
233-0061|It would mean that an algorithm trained on this dataset is trained on a fair dataset.|It would mean that an algorithm trained on this dataset is trained on a fair dataset.
233-0062|So then so then maybe we should just get all the data right? Let's just acquire all the data.|So then so then maybe we should just get all the data right? Let's just acquire all the data.
233-0063|Maybe that's not the right answer either. This has in fact has been shown to be very problematic.|Maybe that's not the right answer either. This has in fact has been shown to be very problematic.
233-0064|The problems arise from these automated ways how the images are sourced for example using large scale Google image search.|The problems arise from these automated ways how the images are sourced for example using large scale Google image search.
233-0065|Which is the data set that we’ve all been using for a very long time.|Which is the data set that we’ve all been using for a very long time.
233-0066|Even if you find other ways of acquiring data some of the data that you actually acquire and in fact some of the problems that we have just seen with this large curation large and automated curation of visual datasets.|Even if you find other ways of acquiring data some of the data that you actually acquire and in fact some of the problems that we have just seen with this large curation large and automated curation of visual datasets.
233-0067|Results from the problems that there are biases and how the data that are then being source and then being mined|Results from the problems that there are biases and how the data that are then being source and then being mined
233-0068|Right? Because of data that has been generated that is available now has been generated using historic processes.| Right? Because of data that has been generated that is available now has been generated using historic processes.
233-0069|And the historic processes that generated this data may not have been ideal.|And the historic processes that generated this data may not have been ideal.
233-0070|The algorithm trained on those datasets would then obviously also exhibit exactly those biases and prejudice.|The algorithm trained on those datasets would then obviously also exhibit exactly those biases and prejudice.
233-0071|So the example that I'm going to give you here is a very famous one, which is the algorithm developed by Amazon. It’s not used any longer because of the problems that we are discussing.|So the example that I'm going to give you here is a very famous one, which is the algorithm developed by Amazon. It’s not used any longer because of the problems that we are discussing.
233-0072|You would like to retrieve the most promising applicants in order to make for example automated hiring decisions.|You would like to retrieve the most promising applicants in order to make for example automated hiring decisions.
233-0073|But there is a whole lot of problems right? Because of dataset that you're basing this on is a dataset that has all the resumes that applied to Amazon.|But there is a whole lot of problems right? Because of dataset that you're basing this on is a dataset that has all the resumes that applied to Amazon.
233-0074|The positive cases that you can use in order to train your algorithm, the people that came to Amazon and actually stayed there, are only the people that can currently deal with it.|The positive cases that you can use in order to train your algorithm, the people that came to Amazon and actually stayed there, are only the people that can currently deal with it.
233-0075|those are the people that somehow cleared the interview process.|those are the people that somehow cleared the interview process.
233-0076|and if that recruitment process is biased then there is no way that you will see cases that could have done well, but they were not selected|and if that recruitment process is biased then there is no way that you will see cases that could have done well, but they were not selected
233-0077|Right? It's not it's not like the country is run by a whole lot of racists.|Right? It's not it's not like the country is run by a whole lot of racists.
233-0078|The way how is things are structured is essentially based on this historic system that is not perfect|The way how is things are structured is essentially based on this historic system that is not perfect.




